苟潼離劤쳄양俚캥，쓴헝련狂
www.tvsubtitles.net
The fist of the First Men.
Thousands of years ago,
the First Men stood here.
They came here to get
away from something.
And I don't think it worked.
Your sword.
The Kingslayer,
he escaped in the night.
How?
Jaime Lannister has
played you for a fool.
Sansa and Arya are captives
in King's Landing.
Returning him may buy
life for my children.
A girl owes one more name.
Give a man a name.
- Jaqen H'ghar.
- A girl gives a man his own name?
I'll un-name you if you help
me and my friends escape.
A girl and her friends will
walk through the gate at midnight.
Who was that out there
hung up at the gates?
Must have been
the farmer's boys.
Killed them, burned them,
and passed them off
as the little lords?
Got as far as the farm
then doubled back.
Hoped this would be the last
place they'd think to look.
My bastard is only a few
days from Winterfell.
- Once he captures the castle--
- Theon has my brothers.
- If we storm the castle--
- he wouldn't dare hurt the boys.
There is only hope of escaping
the North with his head.
Send word to your son.
Any Ironborn
who surrender will be allowed
to return safely
to their homes.
With the exception
of Theon Greyjoy.
I expect his countrymen will turn on
him the minute they hear the offer.
Mance is gonna march
on the wall.
When he does,
one brother inside his army
will be worth 1,000
fighting against him.
- They'll never trust me.
- They might.
- If you do what needs to be done.
- What?
I should have known better,
trusting a traitor's bastard!
He's not yours
to kill, crow.
I don't want to marry
the Frey girl.
I don't want you
to marry her.
If you enter that place,
you will never leave again.
If my dragons are in
the House of the Undying,
then take me there.
That's what
the warlock wants.
- His magic is strong.
- And what of my magic?
They're coming ashore.
There are too many.
Rain fire on them.
The battle is over.
We have won.
( Theme music playing )
?? Game of Thrones 2x10 ??
Valar Morghulis
Original Air Date on June 3, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
??
Pod.
Pod!
Find Bronn or Varys.
Tell them I am here
with Maester Pycelle.
Tell them I am
very much alive.
Yes, My Lord.
Would you like
something for the pain?
What happened?
The murderer and traitor
Stannis Baratheon
suffered a stunning defeat
at the hands of your father.
Where am I?
These are your new chambers.
A little cramped,
perhaps,
but you don't need
much room, do you?
You are no longer
Hand of the King.
Oh.
For your trouble.
I, Joffrey of the House
Baratheon, first of my name,
the rightful King
of the Andals
and the First Men,
Lord of the Seven
Kingdoms
and protector
of the Realm,
do hereby proclaim
my grandfather
Tywin Lannister
the savior of the city
and the Hand of the King.
Thank you, Your Grace.
Lord Petyr Baelish,
step forward.
For your good service
and ingenuity
in uniting the Houses
of Lannister and Tyrell,
I declare that you shall be granted
the castle of Harrenhal...
With all its attendant
lands and incomes
to be held by your sons
and grandsons
from this day until
the end of time.
You honor me
beyond words, Your Grace.
I shall have to acquire
some sons and grandsons.
Ser Loras Tyrell.
Your House has come
to our aid.
The whole realm
is in your debt,
none more so than I.
If your family would ask
anything of me, ask it
and it shall be yours.
Your Grace,
my sister Margaery,
her husband was taken
from us before...
She remains innocent.
I would ask you to
find it in your heart
to do us the great honor
of joining our Houses.
Is this what you want,
Lady Margaery?
With all my heart,
Your Grace.
I have come to love
you from afar.
Tales of your
courage and wisdom
have never been
far from my ears.
And those tales have taken
root deep inside of me.
Well, I too have heard tales
of your beauty and grace,
but the tales
do not do you justice,
My Lady.
It would be an honor
to return your love,
but I am promised
to another.
A King must keep
his word.
Your Grace, in the judgment
of your small council,
it would be neither
proper nor wise
for you to wed the daughter
of a man beheaded for treason,
a girl whose brother
is in open rebellion
against the throne
as we speak.
For the good
of the realm,
your councilors
beg you...
to set Sansa Stark aside.
- Margaery!
- We want Margaery!
I would like to heed
your wishes
and the wishes
of my people,
but I took
a holy vow.
Your Grace,
the Gods do indeed
hold betrothal solemn,
but your father,
blessed be his memory,
made this pact
before the Starks
revealed their falseness.
I have consulted
with the High Septon
and he assures me that their
crimes against the realm
free you from any promise
you have made to them
in the sight
of the Gods.
The Gods are good.
I am free
to heed my heart.
Ser Loras, I will gladly
wed your sweet sister.
You will be my Queen
and I will love you
from this day
until my last day.
My Lady.
My sincerest condolences.
They're right--
I'm not good enough for him.
You shouldn't say that.
You'll be good enough
for many things.
He'll still enjoy
beating you.
And now that
you're a woman,
he'll be able to enjoy you
in other ways as well.
But if he's not
marrying me--
He'll let you go home?
Joffrey's not the sort of boy
who gives away his toys.
You have a tender heart,
just like your mother
did at your age.
I can see so much
of her in you.
She was like
a sister to me.
For her sake,
I'll help get you home.
King's Landing
is my home now.
Look around you.
We're all liars here.
And every one of us
is better than you.
Come in.
Make yourself
comfortable.
That doesn't look
very comfortable.
Here, watch me.
No need for that,
my dear.
You sure?
Most men like
what they see.
I'm not like
most men.
That's what most men say.
If you don't want
what most men want,
then you'd better tell me
what you'd like me to do.
I would like you to tell me
if working for Lord Baelish
has been all you'd
hoped it would be.
Have we met?
You wouldn't
remember me if we had?
I meet a lot of men.
And I think you
remember all of them.
I think your true talents
are wasted on them.
You're very kind,
My Lord.
Allow me to return
the favor.
You're afraid.
Why?
Nothing dangerous down there.
I know who you are.
And, unlike your
current employer,
I protect those
who work for me.
I don't abuse them
to satisfy royal whims
or force them
to abuse each other.
How do you know
about that?
I thought you said
you knew who I was.
What can I do for you,
Lord Varys?
Littlefinger looks at you
and sees a collection
of profitable holes.
I see a potential
partner.
- I'm afraid of him.
- Oh, you should be.
He's a dangerous man.
But everyone has
their weaknesses.
Your current employer
hides his very well,
but not as well
as he thinks.
You're a virgin,
I take it?
Walk.
Childhood must have
been awful for you.
Were you a foot taller
than all the boys?
They laughed at you,
called you names?
Some boys
like a challenge.
One or two must have
tried to get inside big Brienne.
- One or two tried.
- Ah.
But you fought them off.
But maybe you wished one
of them could overpower you,
fling you down,
tear off your clothes.
But none of them
were strong enough.
- I'm strong enough.
- Not interested.
Of course you are.
You'd love to know what it
feels like to be a woman.
Ah. "They lay
with lions."
Tavern girls, I'd say.
Probably served
my father's soldiers.
Maybe one of them
gave up a kiss and a feel.
That's how
they earned this.
The glorious work of the
northern freedom fighters.
Must make you proud
to serve the Starks.
I don't serve the Starks.
I serve Lady Catelyn.
Tell yourself that tonight
when they swing in your dreams.
- What are you doing?
- Burying them.
We shouldn't stay here.
We should get back on the river.
I think these women
would understand if--
I don't care
what you think.
I didn't leave it here.
Untie me now.
I gave it to you to cut
the rope, and now I don't
have me dagger no more.
So unless it got stuck in your ass
on its way to your cunt,
it stands to reason
that it's gone-- whoa!
What's your business here?
Traveling a prisoner.
You're a woman.
A woman!
Well, fuck me!
If you've quite
finished up--
All right,
we'll be going.
Whoa, whoa.
Who do you fight for?
The Starks.
What did he do?
Apparently eating is now a crime.
Who knew?
No, stealing is a crime.
But it's not a crime to starve.
That's justice for you.
- Where are you taking him?
- To Riverrun.
Why Riverrun?
Steal from the Tullys,
it's their dungeons you rot in.
- Why not kill him?
- For stealing a pig?
I don't give the orders.
He must be important
to someone.
Sending him with you?
How important could he be?
All right,
have it your way,
m'lady.
- Do I know you?
- Have you been to Ashemark?
- No.
- Then you don't know me.
Do you ever go to the river
market at Salt Rock?
- Is it near Ashemark?
- No.
I've never been there.
What do you think
of these beauties?
I hope you gave them
quick deaths.
Two of them we did, yeah.
Wait.
I do know you.
That's Jaime Lannister.
I wish someone had told me.
I wouldn't have had
to steal that pig.
If this is the Kingslayer,
I think I'd know about it.
How do you know what
the Kingslayer looks like?
I was at Whispering Wood.
I saw him.
They dragged him out of the woods
and threw him down before the King.
He's not the Kingslayer.
Sorry to disappoint you.
If he was, I'd only
be traveling his head.
I have a question
for you both.
And I want you to answer it
at the same time.
I count to three,
you both answer.
What's his name?
One.
Two. Three.
Two quick deaths.
Those were Stark men.
I don't serve the Starks.
I serve Lady Catelyn.
I told her I'd take you
to King's Landing,
and that's what
I'm going to do.
Stay.
Walder Frey is a dangerous
man to cross.
I know that.
And you mean
to do it anyway?
I love her.
I know that seems
important to you.
It is important to me.
Your father didn't love
me when we married.
He hardly knew me
or I him.
Love didn't just
happen to us.
We built it slowly
over the years,
stone by stone,
for you, for your
brothers and sisters,
for all of us.
It's not as exciting as
secret passion in the woods,
but it is stronger.
It lasts longer.
And that is what
would be in store for me
with one of
Walder Frey's daughters,
- what you and father had?
- Why not?
Because she's not beautiful?
Because she's not exotic
and exciting?
Now you're arguing just to argue
because you arranged it.
And you agreed to it.
You gave him your word.
Treat your oaths recklessly and
your people will do the same.
If your father lived
his life for one thing--
My father is dead.
And the only parent
I have left has no right
to call anyone reckless.
You said you saw
my victory in the flames.
I did.
- I still see it.
- The flames lied.
And I'm no better
than a savage
trusting in a Fire God.
I fought for your God
in Blackwater Bay.
I led my men to the gates
of the Seventh Hell
as their brothers burned
alive, and for what?
Attacked from behind by
Tywin Lannister and the Tyrells.
If you see so much in your flames,
why didn't you warn me?
The Lord of Light
only allows me glimpses.
You claimed to speak
for a God.
Will you quit the war just
because you've lost a battle?
You talk about war
as if you understand it.
I've been fighting
far longer than you.
Have you?
Show me how you fight.
Show me.
Where's your God now?
Will he save you?
Where is your God?
Inside you.
I murdered my brother.
We murdered him.
Share the weight
with me.
He wasn't your brother.
This war
has just begun.
It will last for years.
Thousands will die
at your command.
You will betray
the men serving you.
your family.
You will betray everything
you once held dear.
And it will all
be worth it
because you are
the Son of Fire.
You are the Warrior
of Light.
You will sweep aside
this pretender and that one.
You will be King.
You promise
these things, but...
you don't know.
None of us know.
Let me show you.
Look into the fire,
my King.
Look.
I see fire.
Keep looking.
Do you see?
Do you see, my King?
Yes.
I will kill that man.
I don't care how many arrows
they feather me with,
how many spears
they run through me,
I will kill that horn-blowing
cunt before I fall.
They want you to know
you're surrounded.
I know I'm surrounded.
I know that because I stood
on the battlements
and saw I was surrounded.
They don't want
you to sleep.
They want to sap
your spirit before--
Thank you, wise bald man.
Thank you for explaining
siege tactics to me.
No word from my father?
No.
Send more ravens.
You killed
all the ravens.
The first time
I saw Winterfell...
I saw Winterfell,
it looked like something
that had been here for
thousands of years
and would be here
for thousands of years
after I was dead.
I saw it
and I thought,
"of course Ned Stark
crushed our rebellion
and killed my brothers.
We never stood a chance against
a man who lives here."
Lord Stark went out of his way
to make it your home.
Yes, my captors were
so very kind to me.
You love
reminding me of that.
Everyone in this
frozen pile of shit
has always loved
reminding me of that.
You know what it's like
to be told how lucky you are
to be someone's prisoner?
To be told how much
you owe them?
And then to go back home
to your real father...
I will kill that man.
I swear it to
the Drowned God,
the Old Gods,
the New Gods,
to every fucking God
in every fucking heaven,
I will kill that man.
Theon, listen to me.
I serve Winterfell.
Now Winterfell is yours.
I'm bound by oath
to serve you.
And what's your counsel,
trusted friend?
Run.
500 Northmen wait
outside the walls.
You have 20 men.
You can't win.
Wait for nightfall
and run.
There's nowhere to run.
I'd never make it back
to the Iron Islands.
And even if I did,
even if by some miracle
I slipped through the lines
and made it home,
I'd be a coward.
The Greyjoy who ran.
The shame of the family.
Don't go home.
Join the Night's Watch.
Once a man
has taken the Black...
he's beyond reach
of the law.
All his past crimes
are forgiven.
I won't make it
to the Wall.
I won't make it 10 feet
past the Winterfell gates.
There are ways.
Hidden passageways built
so the Lords of Winterfell
could escape.
The road will be dangerous.
But with a little luck...
the Night's Watch is an ancient,
honorable order.
You'll have
opportunities there.
The opportunity for Jon Snow
to cut my throat in my sleep.
The opportunity to make
amends for what you've done.
I've done a lot,
haven't I?
Things I never
imagined myself doing.
I've known you many years,
Theon Greyjoy.
You're not the man
you're pretending to be.
Not yet.
You may be right.
But I've gone too far
to pretend to be anything else.
You hear that?
That's the mating call
of the Northmen.
They want to fuck us.
Well, I haven't had
a good fuck in weeks.
I'm ready for one.
They say every Ironborn man is
worth a dozen from the mainland.
Aye!
- You think they're right?
- Aye.
We die today, brothers.
We die bleeding
from 100 wounds
with arrows in our necks
and spears in our guts,
but our war cries will echo
through eternity.
They will sing about
the battle of Winterfell
until the Iron Islands have
slipped beneath the waves.
Every man, woman, and child
will know who we were
and how long we stood.
Aggar and Gelmarr;
Wex and Urzen;
Stygg and Black Lorren--
Ironborn warriors
will cry out our names
as they leap onto the shores
of Seagard and Faircastle.
Aye!
- Mothers will name their sons for us.
- Aye!
Girls will think of us
with their lovers inside them.
Aye!
And whoever kills
that fucking horn-blower
will stand in bronze
above the shores of Pyke!
Aye!
- What is dead may never die!
Ah!
Thought he'd never shut up.
It was a good speech.
Didn't want to interrupt.
What is this?
What are you doing?
Let's go home.
Come on.
Why should I believe you?
Why would I lie
about it?
To create strife between
my sister and me.
Where before there was
nothing but love.
Ser Mandon Moore tried to kill
you on your sister's orders.
If it weren't for your
Squire's bravery,
you'd be a dead man.
- Pod.
- Yes, My Lord?
Would it be
excessive of me
to ask you to save
my life twice in a week?
No, My Lord.
You're a good lad.
Get Bronn, tell him I want
four of his most loyal
Gold Cloaks outside
my door at all times.
I'm afraid your friend
has been relieved
of his command
of the City Watch.
The Gold Cloaks are now firmly
in the hands of your father
or your sister.
It varies
from cloak to cloak.
- Then my hill tribesmen.
- Have gone home.
Your father paid them
quite handsomely.
I'm afraid we won't
be seeing each other
for some time, My Lord.
Don't want to swim too close
to a drowning man?
And I thought
we were friends.
We are.
Podrick, would you mind?
There are many who know
that without you
this city faced
certain defeat.
The King won't give
you any honors,
the histories
won't mention you,
but we will not forget.
Come along now, Podrick.
My love.
It was good of you
to come.
Good of me?
Of course I come.
- I want to see you.
- Believe me, you don't.
Have you looked?
I will be the first.
Well?
You are a mess.
I'm a monster
as well as a dwarf.
You should charge
me double.
You think I'm here
for money?
That was the arrangement
we made.
I pay you
and you lie to me.
Aw, I'm a poor
little rich man
and nobody loves me,
so I make jokes all the time
and pay them to laugh.
Fuck your money.
Let's leave.
- Leave?
- Leave King's Landing.
They tried to kill you.
They will try again.
Going into wars,
fighting soldiers--
you're terrible at this.
Let's take a boat to Pentos
and never come back.
You don't belong here.
What would we do
in Pentos?
Eat, drink,
fuck, live.
I want to go with you.
So do it.
Your father, your sister,
all these bad people,
they can't stop you.
Forget about them.
Come with me.
I can't.
I do belong here.
These bad people
are what I'm good at.
Outtalking them,
outthinking them.
It's what I am.
And I like it.
I like it more than
anything I've ever done.
Are you going to leave?
You have a shit memory.
I am yours
and you are mine.
In the sight
of the Seven,
I hereby seal
these two souls,
binding them as one
for eternity.
Look upon one another
and say the words.
Father, smith,
warrior, mother,
maiden, crone,
stranger...
- I am hers and she is mine...
- I am his and he is mine...
from this day
until the end of my days.
Is this a riddle?
Khaleesi!
Are you trying to frighten me
with magic tricks?
You want me?
Here I am.
Are you afraid
of a little girl?
How did he find us?
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
How did you know
we'd come this way?
After all the things
you have seen,
this is your question?
How did you
kill those guards?
Was it hard?
No harder than taking a new name
if you know the way.
Show me how. I want
to be able to do it, too.
If you would learn,
you must come with me.
Where?
Far and away across
the Narrow Sea to Braavos.
My dancing master
was from Braavos.
To be a dancing master
is a special thing,
but to be a faceless man--
that is something
else entirely.
A girl has many names
on her lips--
Joffrey, Cersei,
Tywin Lannister,
Ilyn Payne, the Hound.
Names to offer up
to the Red God.
She could offer them all
one by one.
I want to.
But I can't.
I need to find
my brother and mother.
And my sister.
I need to find
her, too.
Then we must part.
A man has duties as well.
Here.
What is it?
A coin of great value.
Could it buy a horse?
It is not meant
for the buying of horses.
Then what good is it?
If the day comes when
you must find me again,
just give that coin
to any man from Braavos
and say these words to him,
"Valar Morghulis."
Valar Morghulis.
Please don't go, Jaqen.
Jaqen is dead.
Say it again.
Valar Morghulis.
Good.
Farewell, Arya Stark.
Osha, what are you doing?
Tell us what medicine
to get from your chambers.
- We'll make you better.
- I feel just fine.
They burned it down.
They burned everything.
Not everything.
Not you.
But they may come back.
You have to go.
Put on your
warmest clothes.
Pack as much food as you
can carry and go north.
North's the wrong way.
Their mother and brother
are south.
We don't know where.
There are too many enemies
in the South.
Go to the Wall
to Jon.
He'll look after you and let your
mother know you're safe.
I don't want to leave you.
No more than I want
to leave you.
I pulled you
into the world.
Both of you.
I've seen both your faces
almost every day since.
And for that, I consider
myself very, very lucky.
Go now with Hodor.
Go on.
I'll be right here.
Hodor.
Osha.
You must protect them.
You're the only one
who can.
You may have to protect
them against your own kind.
I've got no great love
for my own kind.
I'll get you milk
of the poppy.
Tell me where to find it.
I don't want
milk of the poppy.
Do it quickly.
Until the sun
rises in the west
and sets in the east,
until the rivers run dry
and the mountains blow
in the wind like leaves.
They miss their mother.
They want to be with you.
Do you want
to be with them?
You will be.
When your dragons
were born,
our magic
was born again.
It is strongest
in their presence.
And they are strongest
in yours.
You will be with them,
through winter, summer,
and winter again.
Across a thousand
thousand seasons
you will be with them.
And we will be with you
until time comes to an end.
Welcome home,
Daenerys Stormborn.
This is not my home.
My home is across the sea
where my people
are waiting for me.
They will be waiting
a long time.
Dracarys.
We should be there
by sundown.
Won't be a fun
night for you.
Mance knows how
to make crows sing.
If you know what to say,
you might just make it
through the night.
Not talking's
not the way to go.
Careful with that.
You might cut yourself.
Never swung a sword
before, have you?
You look like a baby
with a rattle.
Enough of that!
- Stop!
- Why, traitor?
So you can give Mance Rayder
an invitation to Castle Black?
Let 'em fight.
That's it?
That's what you can do?
You little shit.
Your traitor father
teach you that?
Or was it your whore mother?
We are the Watchers
on the Wall.
You can tell Mance
that's the man who killed
Qhorin Halfhand.
- Burn the body.
- Aye.
You don't want this one
coming back for you.
Come along, Jon Snow.
Time to meet
the King-Beyond-The-Wall.
What the--?
Khaleesi, please.
He said you'd never
leave Qarth alive.
Come.
Nothing.
Thank you,
Xaro Xhoan Daxos.
Thank you for teaching
me this lesson.
I am King of Qarth.
I can help you now,
truly help you.
We can take
the Iron Throne.
- I'll bring you 1,000 ships.
- Please, Khaleesi, I beg you.
All that you have dreamed
is within your reach!
I beg you, please!
- Khaleesi.
- Please! Please!
- Khaleesi!
It's all a lie.
Looks real enough to me.
Real enough
to buy a ship?
Aye, a small ship.
I thought we were coming
north to fight wildlings.
Is this goat?
It's moose.
People shouldn't
live anywhere
you need to burn shit
to keep warm.
Well, you see a tree,
let me know.
If you step back
and think about it,
the thing about Gilly
that's so interesting is--
- Just bloody kill me.
- No, truly.
The thing about her that
I find so interesting is that
after all that
Craster's done to her,
she's still got hope that
life might get better.
The thing about Gilly
that you find so interesting
is that she said
six words to you.
And the thing about you
that I find so interesting
is absolutely nothing.
It's Jon
and the Halfhand.
They're back.
Two blasts is wildlings.
You're not fighting them alone.
Come on.
Three blasts?
Run!
Wait! Wait for me!
Grenn!
Edd!
== sync, corrected by elderman ==